three reasons why Vladivostok
три причины Зачем Владивостоку
should stay with Russia here are three
Оставаться с Россией вот три
reasons today I am conducting such
причины сегодня вот я провожу такие
research about the possible collapse of the
исследования о возможном распаде
Russian Federation What region are you from
Российской Федерации Вот вы с какого
Belgorod region
региона Белгородская область
Belgorod region if, for example,
Белгородская область вот если например
Vladivostok and Khabarovsk announce
Владивосток и Хабаровск так огласят о
independence and the creation of, for example, the
независимости и создания например
Primorsky People's Republic, will
Приморской народной Республики да будете
you  uh, let’s say go to the Volunteers so that the
ли вы э скажем идти в Добровольцы чтобы
military
военным
can force them to stay in the Russian
принудить их остаться в Российской
Federation, these are generally unrealistic things.
Федерации это вообще нереальные вещи Ну
Well, it’s unrealistic that you
что вот нереально что вы пошли
volunteered so that Vladivostok can be returned, this is an
добровольцем чтоб Владивосток вернуть
unrealistic thing, absolutely unrealistic,
это нереальная вещь абсолютно нереально
these dreams of cutting up a carcass are not
эти вот эти мечты по разделке тушки не А
Why why do you look like this after the revolution of
почему почему смотрите после революции
917  and it was the Far Eastern
917 года так и было было Дальневосточная
Republic of Siberia, then Lenin simply
республика Сибирская потом просто Ленин
gathered and made a revolution in Yes and forcibly
собрал сделал революцию в Да и насильно
annexed it all back into Soviet
присоединил назад это всё в советскую
Russia yes And before that Yes there were independent
Россию да А до этого Да были независимые
Republics who
Республики по
agreed Spain once had a
соглашались Испания когда-то была
Spanish crown that controlled almost
испанская корона контролировала чуть ли
all of South America Yes except there
не всю Южную Америку Да кроме там
Brazil has several other regions that
Бразилии ещё нескольких регионов которые
the British controlled there and others are
там британцы контролировали и другие
now independent countries and
сейчас эти страны независимые и живёт
Argentina is Spanish-speaking. Yes, Chile is
Аргентина испаноязычная Да Чили
Spanish-speaking and other countries. Yes, there are
испаноязычная и другие страны Да есть
Spanish-speaking ones and they have nothing to do with
испаноязычные и никакого отношения к
modern Spain, and here too, that
Испании современной не имеют также и тут
is, the Russian Empire, so it will
то есть Империя Российская так будет
remain a fraction beyond that.  there, the
дальше дроби останется какой-то там
Central region, the rest will be
Центральный этот регион остальные будут
independent. Well, there will be a Far Eastern
независимы Ну и будет Дальневосточная
Republic with Russian as the
республика с русским языком
state language, and that will be the same as, for
государственным и что так же как
example, Argentina with
например Аргентина с
Spanish. Well, for hundreds of hundreds of years, Russia
испанским Ну сотни сотни лет Россия
has united all these regions and, as it were,
объединила все эти регионы и как бы
all this has led to mutually beneficial cooperation, and as if the
всё привело и как бы
country continues to exist as  a
страна продолжает существовать как
single whole Look, this is the same thing for hundreds of
единая цела Смотри вот то же самое сотни
years Spain colonized South
лет Испания ээ колонизировал Южную
America Yes, the same people who
Америку Да там живут те же люди которые
come from Spain live there, but after a
выходцы из Испании всё но они через
certain period of time they no longer had any
определённый срок уже не имели никаких
sense in giving anything to Spain and
ээ смыслов отдавать что-то Испании и
declared independence here and there Why would
огласили независимость так и тут Зачем
Vladivostok yes  Moscow, here are three reasons
Владивостоку да Москва вот три причины
I tell you I'll tell you more Why
я тебе Я тебе больше скажу Зачем
Lugansk Donetsk and Kherson and
Луганской Донецкой и Херсонской и
Zaporizhzhia regions let's say Kiev is not here
Запорожской области там допустим Киев не
You're not you're running away you see you're running away
Вот ты не ты убегаешь видишь ты убегаешь
because you have no arguments you have no
потому что у тебя нет аргументов у тебя
arguments why Well, I just don't
нет аргументов почему Ну просто я не
see I don't even see  any prerequisites at all?
вижу Не вижу даже ни каких-то вообще
Well, if not as prerequisites, wait, there are,
предпосылок Ну как не как предпосылок
look, for example, in
подожди есть смотри например в
Khabarovsk there were huge performances.
Хабаровске были огромнейший выступления
Yes, for example, when he got into trouble. Yes, it was a
Да вот например когда зафул Да это был
conflict with the Central government and the
конфликт с Центральной властью и он до
Elites still have it. Yes, because the elites.
сих пор есть у Элит Да потому что элиты
Yes, they also don’t want.  to be
Да также хотят они не хотят просто быть
pawns of Moscow just as the Soviet Union
пешками Москвы так же как Советский Союз
collapsed Yes, the national elites so
развалился Да национальные элиты так
wanted to have real power
захотели э иметь реальную власть на
locally and I don’t know here either You know I
местах так и тут не знаю Ты знаешь я я
don’t want you Well I can’t say anything for sure
тебе не хочу Ну не могу ничего точно
about the elites I just don’t know what the
сказать об элитах Я просто не знаю что
elites are but I think  what are our litas about
такое элиты но я думаю что литы наши про
three three reasons why Vladivostok
три три причины Зачем Владивостоку
should stay with Russia here are
Оставаться с Россией вот
three
три
reasons I can name three why to
причины я могу назвать три зачем
disconnect for example there is more
отсоединиться например там более
economic freedom not to give money
экономическая свобода не отдавать деньги
and resources to Moscow Vladivostok and
и ресурсы в Москву Владивосток и
Primorsky Krai Khabarovsk here everything is
Приморский край Хабаровский вот там всё
economically a very strong region there is a
экономически очень сильный регион есть
sea ocean access to  international
море океан выход к международной
trade USA China Japan South Korea, that
торговли США Китай Япония Южно Корея то
is, where exactly the money is, this
есть там где именно бабки вот этот
Pacific region
Тихоокеанский регион А
Why stay with Moscow, the point is this is
зачем Оставаться с Москвой смысл это же
one people, people who came there from
один народ люди которые пришли там с
Moscow in 1600, where in the forty-fifth year,
Москвы в 1600 там каком соро пятом году
this region was discovered by the same
этот регион открывали это те же самые
people as  the same ones Yes, look, the
люди что и те самые Да так вот смотри те
same people in Chile live the same
же самые люди в Чили живут те же самые
people as in Spain the same ones in Chile in
люди что и в Испании те самые в Чили в
Argentina That's exactly the same people who lived
Аргентине Вот точно те люди которые жили
in Spain are one people you will understand that the
в Испании один народ ты поймешь что те
same Genes are the same Genes people
же самые Гены те же самые Гены люди
who  Absolutely the same Genes, look
которы абсолютно те же самые Гены смотри
in Argentina, the same Genes in the
в Аргентине те же самые Гены что в и
United States of America, the same Genes in
штах амери те же самые Гены что в
Britain, but they
Британии но
disconnected Argentina They are all mulattos
отсоединили Аргентина Они же все мулат
There, they are still the same
Там они же поме всё равно
with Kriol or mulattoes, you know, mulattoes there
с криол или мулаты понимаешь мулаты там
Bula yes Look E times in  that’s not the
Була да Смотри Е раз в этом не в этом
point, that’s the point, the people who live in
суть в этом суть люди которые живут в
Khabarovsk consider themselves to be part of
Хабаровске они считают себя Ну частью
Russia, you understand, because the
России понимаешь потому что и открывали
ancestors of the Argentines discovered this country, expanded this
страну предки аргентинцев расширяли эту
country from Spain, sailed and settled
страну из Испании Приплыли и заселяли
this country, the
эту страну тоже
same thing, no, you don’t understand Australia,
самое Да нету не понимаешь Австралия
New Zealand, yes, these are Genes  the same
Новая Зеландия Да это Гены те же самые
as in Britain Well, people understand
что и в Британии Ну люди понимаешь как
how they can separate it, well, it’s like
те как могу это разъединиться ну как бы
one organism Well, the organism is intact,
один организм Ну так ди целы организм
you understand this Rossi This is a big
это понимаешь это Росси Это большой
organism, such a whole leg separately will
организм такой целый нога отдельно будет
live naked Look, it will just be
жить голо Смотри это будет просто уже
several For example, how
несколько Вот например как как
single-celled amoebas reproduce there. There
размножаются там амёбы одноклеточные Вот
was one organism, they split into two
был один организм оп разделились на два
and live separately and everything is like this and here
и живут отдельно и всё так и тут вот это
you understand this, this is Europe, this is Europe, this is where
понимаешь это вот Европа это Европа это
amoebas live And our body is like this And
вот там вот амёбы живут А у нас организм
what unites look at what
такой А в чём Что объединяет смотри что
unites a resident of Vladivostok and
объединяет жителя Владивостока и
Moskvich Well, by and large, these are
Москвича Ну это ну по большому счёту это
Russian people. Well, in general, yes, in terms of
русские люди Ну в целом Да так вот по по
spirituality, in their morality and in their
духовности по своей морали и по своей
history, in their culture, and well, with
истории по своей культуре и что ну своми
these Well, that’s right, I say it again,
этими Ну правильно я ещё раз говорю
look, a resident of Argentina and a resident of
смотрите житель Аргентины и житель
Spain are the same  Spanish people, according to
Испании - это те же испанские люди по
history, have the roots of religion and so on, but they
истории корнями религии и так дальше но
live separately in a separate state.
живут отдельно в отдельном государства
Well, you see, in Russia there is no such
Ну понимаешь в России нету вот такой
system of consumerism, so it’s as if a
системы потреблятство поэтому как бы
person, for the sake of consumerism, consumes a
человек ради потреблятство потреблять
row of consumerism to abandon part of the
ряди потреблятство отказаться от части
history, partly the
истории отчасти
country of capitalism is not them. Well, you understand, you
стра капитализма не они Ну понимаешь ты
suggest just huddling in what  in the
предлагаешь просто забиться в каком-то
corner someone is eating a hamster and eating lu there
углу кому-то и хомячит и жрать там лу
No look just Vladivostok sri Vladivostok
Нет смотри как раз владиво сри
Vladivostok will then be able to
Владивосток Владивосток сможет тогда
develop normally spiritually without
духовно развиваться нормально без
Moscow Because the money, look, the money
Москвы Потому что деньги смотри деньги
that goes to Moscow will
которые забираются в Москву да будут
remain in Vladivostok,
оставаться во Владивостоке будут
theaters will be built, schools will be built,
строиться театры школы
yes, budgets will be
да да бюджеты так
replenished like that  Nega DB that Vladivostok
Пополняется Нега БД что Владивосток
receives from Moscow,
получает от Москвы
what do you understand, you are talking about how to
что ты понимаешь ты рассуждаешь как
consume Well, I understand, I’m telling you, you are
потреблять Ну что понима Я тебе говорю
talking about how, Moscow
ты рассуждаешь как поб те Москва
receives from Vladivostok and Vladivostok
получает от Владивостока а Владивосток
from Moscow. No, that’s
от Москвы Нет
right. Well, you see, I don’t know how
правильно Ну понимаешь я не знаю как
it goes. Moscow turns out to consume in
дется Москва оказывается потреблять в
Moscow to be consumed by it.  okay, yes,
Москве быть потреблять ею нормально да
Moscow receives all the resources from all regions
Москва получает со всех регионов всё
and don’t tell me what to consume the code of
ресурсы и не говори что потреблять кода
SM Moscow with what the hell are they?
СМ Москва с что
Our regions earn differently
такие ну блин У нас регионы по-разному
for spiritually and materially. What Moscow
за духовно материально Что даёт Москва
gives to Vladivostok three reasons. Why should Vladivostok stay with Moscow? what does it get from
получает от
Moscow? good You  you want to say that let’s say
Моск хорошо Ты хочешь сказать что
Well, there are regions, Yes, we have
допустим Ну есть регионы Да у нас
so-called subsidized regions and
которые дотационные так называемые и
Russia should just give up on them
России стоит от них просто отказаться
because they earn little. Yes, and
потому что они мало зарабатывают Да и
as part of the hand that
как сть свою часть рука которая там
got sick there, it
приболела
means that the subsidized subsidized regions
значит дотационные дотационные регионы
are a scam. Why. Because
это обманка Почему Потому что
they all pay taxes because they are subsidized.  to the
дотационные они все платят налоги в
federal budget and to local budgets
федеральный бюджет и в местные бюджеты
Yes, and part of the difference in the
Да и часть разницы
shortage of resources from the DB places they are compensated by
нехватки выт из мест БД им компенсируют
a subvention from the Federal Yes, but
субвенция из Федерального Да но баланс
they still give the balance to the federal budget more
они ВС равно отдают федеральный больше
than they receive from the Federal, that’s all, there are
чем получают из Федерального вот и всё
no subsidized regions from
нету никаких дотационный регионов со
all regions Moscow eats the juice
всех регионов Москва жрёт сок
the only subsidized region  - this is
единственный дотационный регион - это
Moscow, the only Moscow. I don’t know, I
Москва единственный Москва Я не знаю я
can’t tell you for sure right now.
тебе не могу сейчас точно
Look, why why is Moscow the
сказать обя Смотри Почему почему Москва
richest region because, for
самый богатый регион потому что просто
example, it just
например
has offices all over Russia, including
имеет офисы по всей России в том числе и
in Vladivostok, yes And the tax on
во Владивостоке да А налог на при налог
income tax is platt in Moscow.  and that’s it,
на прибыль платт в Москве вот и всё да
look Moscow Yes, Vladivostok feeds,
смотрите Москва Да кормит Владивосток
feeds there, I
кормит там это
really understand how it works, you understand,
правда понял как это работает понимаешь
but again, the economy of Moscow must be
но опять-таки экономика Москвы надо
looked at What is the economy of Moscow and so
смотреть Какая экономика Москвы и так
on,
далее
retail trade is calculated And what does
исчисляется розничная торговля А что
Spain add to the bidding discord,
Испания добавляет розни торгов
so we’ll take a lot from Vladivostok
вот мы воз возьмём с Владивосток
Vladivostok and the port is huge  uh, maritime
Владивосток да порт огромная ээ морская
trade Yes, the gateway to the Pacific
торговля Да ворота в тихоокеанскую
economic environment, yes, sea mining,
экономическую среду да морская добыча
like fish there, and so on, Yes, the entire
как и там рыба и так дальше Да всего
region, Yes, there are huge different resources there, both
региона Да огромные ресурсы там разные и
forests and minerals. Yes, there in the
лесные и полезные ископаемые Да там на
Far East, like there is everything, there
Дальнем Востоке типа есть всё там как
is just enormous potential, yes And there
раз есть огромнейший потенциал да И там
is  economics
есть экономика
Listen, I’ll tell you more You
Послушай вот я тебе больше скажу
understand, this is all the potential, this is
Понимаешь вот эти все потенциал вот этот
all this Huge potential Please
весь Огромный потенциал Пожалуйста
come in Ukraine Poland come into our
входите Украина Польша входите в наш
composition Take advantage there
состав Пользуйтесь
is not a single reason Why Vladivostok
нету ни одной причины Зачем Владивостоку
Should stay with Moscow and you run away
Оставаться с Москвой и ты убегаешь
that’s why in Poland and so on anyway Let’s go
поэтому на Польше и так дальше всё-таки
ahead  let's finish with the question, I'm
Давай вки мы закончим с вопро я те
just saying, come on, let's go back to
просто говорю давай давай мы вернёмся к
that, you tell me three reasons, at least two, I'll
тому ты скажи три причины хотя бы две я
make you an indulgence, a subsidy, I'll give you
тебе сделаю поблажку субсидию даю тебе
two reasons. Why should Vladivostok
две причины Зачем Владивостоку
stay with Moscow? What does Moscow give to
Оставаться с Москвой Что даёт Москва
Vladivostok? The first reason is
Владивостоку первая причина это
genetically the same people who live in
генетически те же самые люди что живут в
Moscow.  and in Central Russia it’s
Москве и в Центральной России это Это
just the same people, one country of
просто те же самые люди одна страна
understanding, these are the people who opened in 1645.
понима это те люди которые в 1645 году
I don’t understand why, for example, a
открывали Я не понимаю зачем например
resident of Vladivostok would give money to a
жителю Владивостока отдавать деньги
Muscovite or a Chechen or a Kadyrovite simply because
москвичу или чеченцу да кадыровцу просто
someone was once 300 years old
из-за того что когда-то кто-то 300 лет
ago there was someone there and the
назад кого-то там имел и
republic multiplied for this entire country of
республике за всю эту страну
ours because no look because in
нашу потому что нет смотри потому что в
Chechnya in Chechnya Yes there is an occupation
Чечне в Чечне Да идёт оккупационный
regime the Russian administration
режим российский состав администрации во
headed by Kadyrov Yes that’s all why he is an
главе Кадырова Да вот и всё почему он
occupation occupation yes because
оккупационный оккупационная да потому
yes Chechnya Chechnya was captured by Khasavyurt
что да Чечню Чечню захватили хасавьюрт
you withdrew troops from What
вы вывели войска из Какие
occupations people live there captured Chechnya
захваты люди живут там захватили Чечня
independent Ichkeria was proclaimed
независимая Ичкерия была провозглашена
Yes, but this is not the topic now, this is now
Да но сейчас не тема это сейчас
Vladivostok, I’m catching up with you so that you don’t
Владивосток я тебя догоняю чтобы ты не
jump on other topics, which means once again
прыгал по другим тем значит ещё раз
Vladivostok is giving resources to Moscow What
Владивосток отдаёт ресурсы Москве Что
Moscow is giving Vladivostok Rome also
даёт Москва Владивосток Роме того
says that we have  once upon a time there was some Great-
говорит что у нас когда-то был какой-то
Grandfather, wait, well, you understand again,
Прадедушка подожди Ну ты опять Понимаешь
here you have a lawsuit. This is broken
вот у вас иска Вот это сломанное
European thinking. Why not why does
мышление европейско Почему не почему
Moscow consume money for this in
Москва по потребляет у на это на
Vladivostok, and Vladivostok
Владивостоке а Владивосток ничего не
receives nothing from Moscow, look again, Moscow
получает от Москвы ещё раз смотри Москва
takes resources from Vladivostok, taxes
забирает из Владивостока ресурсы налоги
and  people What does Moscow give in return, just a
и людей Что даёт Москва взамен просто
simple question to Vladivostok Nako I know
простой вопрос Владивостоку Нако Я знаю
the east now needs, on the contrary,
востоку сейчас необходимы наоборот
resources for the development of this region, on the
ресурсы для развития этого региона туда
contrary, they are giving out hectares of land there
наоборот выдают там гектарами землю
now they are giving out hectares in these regions
сейчас выдают в этих регионах гектарами
please come take a hectare
пожалуйста приезжайте берите гектар
for free once again a hectare of land is given out from a
бесплатно ещ раз гектар земли выдают от
person Well, to everyone everyone Russia
человека Ну Каждому каждому Россия
Moscow  and Moscow doesn’t give it away. Well,
Москва причём Москва же не выдаёт Ну ещё
once again, what does Moscow give to Vladivostok, you are either
раз что даёт Москва Владивостоку ты или
stupid or just being a fool,
глупый или просто придуривается вот
look, I repeat once again Moscow
смотри я ещё раз повторяю Москва
takes Vladivostok gives Moscow resources
забирает Владивосток даёт Москве ресурсы
Yes, uh, money and people’s taxes, yes What does
Да ээ деньги и налоги людей да Что даёт
Moscow give in return to
взамен Москва
Vladivostok? Moscow is a center where
Владивостоку Москва - это центр где
they can accumulate what  -the resources
могут аккумулировать какие-то ресурсы
for
для
Dana gives this is what she can give,
Дане даёт это мого что она может давать
I tell you again, she gives flows and so on, now
я тебе ещё раз говорю даёт потоки и так
you said everything
Дале вот вот вот вот ты сказал всё что
you need, nothing that she can give super
нужно ничего что она может давать супер
So we are undercut Vladivostok gives
Значит мы подрез Владивосток даёт в
money in Moscow, natural resources and people
Москве деньги ресурсы природные и людей
Moscow  doesn’t give Vladivostok anything
Москва не даёт Владивостоку ничего
because it can give So
потому что что она может давать Значит
it doesn’t need dates just Iron
она не нужна даты просто Железный
Man just wooden iron
человек просто деревянной железной
logic Well done to you
логикой Молодец тебе
too So the Russians and I come to the
тоже Итак мы с россиянами приходим к
conclusion that Vladivostok doesn’t need Moscow
выводу что Москва не нужна Владивостоку
Vladivostok needs Moscow but not
Владивосток нужен в Москве но не
the other way around
наоборот
and
да
the Russians can’t explain Why
россияне не могут объяснить Зачем
To Vladivostok Moscow Yes, here he is talking Oh, it’s
Владивостоку Москва Да вот он говорит О
so interesting right away, what is this, what kind of
сразу так интересно сразу а что это что
consumerism is this? Yes, what kind of
это за потреблятство Да что это за
consumerism is this? Well, wait, Moscow, when it
потреблятство Да ну подожди Москва когда
looks at this Vladivostok, it
смотрит на э этот на Владивосток она
looks from the position of consumerism,
смотрит с позиции потреблятство
take taxes, take away living resources there,
забрать налоги забрать живые ресурсы там
well, in kind, and what kind  -then, minerals,
ну в натуре да какие-то э полезные
seafood, forest, and so on. Yes,
ископаемые морепродукты лес и так дальше
to take people there, including to
Да забрать людей в том числе там на
war, for example, for some kind of
войну например на свои какие-то
imperial ambitions, yes. In order to
имперские амбиции да Для того чтобы
capture new regions. And what does
захватывать новые регионы А что получает
Vladivostok get in return? So, each
Владивосток что Итак каждый
region, most regions don’t give a
регион большинству регионов насрали в
[ __ ] about what they  subsidized regions Yes,
уши что они дотационные регионы Да что
they won’t survive there Yes, of them, it’s just
они там не выживут Да из них просто
the economy of Moscow, here is the oil
экономика Москвы вот нефтяной
Bashkartastan,
башкартастан
subsidized, and Moscow, which has no
дотационный а Москва которая без
resources Yes, it stands on some river Vonyuchki
ресурсов Да на какой-то речке Вонючки
It’s economically bam-bam-bam
стоит Она экономически бам-бам-бам
geniuses of the economy So the
гении экономики Так
peoples of Russia, including the USA
что народы России да в том числе вот США
this is genetic genetic Yes, the Russian
это генетический генетический Да русский
world is some kind of yes That is, Muscovites to you Yes,
мир какой-то да То есть Вам москвичи Да
Vladivostok residents say that you need to be
владивостокцы говорят что вас нужно
robbed because once upon a time someone
грабить потому что когда-то у кого-то
had some kind of common grandfather somewhere 500 years ago,
был где-то там 500 лет назад какой-то
so now you have to
общий дедушка поэтому вы теперь должны
work for Muscovites  It’s not
работать На москвичей не
mutually beneficial to work for Muscovites and there’s
взаимовыгодно работать На москвичей и
nothing wrong with the Independence of the
ничего страшного нету в Независимости
Far East and Siberia, yes, there is a
Дальнего Востока и Сибири да есть вот
principle Look, Yes, there was a Spanish
принцип Посмотрите Да была испанская
Empire, they became a Spanish-speaking state, and it’s
Империя стали государство испаноязычные
Spanish-blent and that’s it, in Chile they speak
да испано бланте и всё и в Чили говорят
Spanish in Argentina, they speak Spanish
на испанском в Аргентине говорят на
Yes, in Cuba they speak Spanish, that’s it
испанском Да в кубе говорят на испанском
the same genetically the same
это те же генетически те же самые
Spaniards who came yes The same thing
Испанцы которые приезжали да Тоже самое
and live normally and perform in
и живут нормально и выступают и в
football matches and at the Olympics and
футбольных матчах и на Олимпиадах и
develop Yes And they leave money in
развиваются Да И деньги оставляют в
their countries in their regions they
своих странах в своих регионах они
send it across the sea to Spain USA
отправляют через море в Испанию США
United States Yes they appeared as a
Соединённые Штаты Да появились как в
result  the struggle for independence from
результате борьбы за независимость от
Britain
Британии
and the United States of Siberia will appear as a
и Соединённые Штаты Сибири появятся в
result of the collapse of the Russian
результате распада Российской
Empire and the Far Eastern Republic And
Империи и Дальневосточная республика И
so
так дальше
carry on
дерзайте